前情提要
Previously on house.
我不记得怎么到这里的
I don't know how I got here.
我在撞车前看见了症状
I saw a symptom before the crash.
我为什么会坐巴士?
Why was I taking the bus?
医学催眠可以让大脑处于/二级δ脑电波状态
medical hypnosis can bring the/brain to a class two theta state.
你在折磨一个已经伤痕累累的大脑
taxing an already injured brain.
因为我的失忆 有人正在濒死边缘
Someone is dying because/I can't remember.
那个人是Amber/她当时和我一起在巴士上
it was amber. She was/on the bus with me.
她是那个快死的人
She's the one who's dying.
她的心跳很快
her heart won't stop racing.
不知道是什么原因
No idea what's causing it.
你肯定不是撞车导致的?
Sure it wasn't the/bus that landed on her?
不是外伤 手术后情况稳定
It's not trauma. She/was stable post-op.
- 这是一小时前开始的/- 老天
- This didn't start until an hour ago./- Oh, my god.
对外伤的延迟反应
delayed reaction to the trauma.
她在车祸中失去了两边肾
She lost both her/kidneys in the bus crash.
并且股动脉撕裂
She ripped upher femoral artery.
我们对修复了血管/用透析机取代肾脏功能
We fixed the artery, got her/on dialysis for the kidneys.
肯定不是车祸造成了心动过速
Whatever's doing this to her/heart, it isn't from the crash.
- 钾查了吗?/- 当然
- Check her potassium?/- Of course.
你们为什么不通知我?
Why didn't you call me?
她一直没有恢复意识/而且身上没有身份证
She's been under the whole/time. She had no I.D.
注射腺苷了没?
pushed adenosine?
还注射了异搏停/并在1小时前置入了漂浮导管
And verapamil, and/floated the swan an hour ago.
冠状动脉血管造影呢?
Coronary angiography?
有3个临危病人排在她前面/1小时内会轮到她
Three critical patients ahead of her./We'll have her in within the hour.
坐救护车我们15分钟能赶到/普林斯顿教学医院
We're 15 minutes away from/princeton plainsboro by ambulance.
你要搬动她?/她的心率是130
You want to move her?/Her heart rate is 130.
她的生命征象稳定/我们要带她走
She's hemodynamically/stable. We're moving her.
你不是她的医生/没权力做这个决定
You're not her doctor. You/can't make that decision.
她的丈夫有
Her husband can.
对不对?
Right?
带她走
Move her.
- 如果外伤没有损害她的心脏--/- 她为什么会在巴士上?
- If the trauma didn't damage her/heart- - why was she on the bus?
我不知道 如果她有别的隐患/车祸也许使它加剧了
I don't know. If she had any underlying/condition, the accident could have exacerbated it.
- 你为什么会和她在一起?/- 我不知道!
- Why were you with her?/- I don't know!
我不想隐瞒什么/我只是不记得了
I'm not hiding anything./I just don't remember.
还有什么会损害她的心脏?
What else could damage her heart?
Wilson 别分神
Wilson, don't get lost.
我好容易才没垮下/现在亟需你帮忙
I'm barely coherent. I/need your help right now.
室颤
V-fib.
- 充电/- 好吧 好吧
- Charging./- Okay. Okay.
- 让开/- 等等 等等
- Clear./- Wait, wait, wait.
亚低温脑保护
Protective hypothermia.
你想冷冻她?
You want to freeze her?
- 她的心脏停止了/- 她的心脏已经损伤了
- Her heart's not beating./- Her heart's already damaged.
如果重启它 让它继续过速跳动/便会释放出自由基 杀死她的大脑
If you restart it, it'll keep racing, shoot/off free radicals, and kill her brain.
我们冷冻她并进行旁路循环/直至你对她确诊为止
We ice her down,put her on/bypass until you've diagnosed her.
这不是解决问题的办法
This is not a solution.
你所做的一切只是为了拖延
All you're doing is pressing pause.
这可以给你更多时间找出病因
It gives you more/time to find a diagnosis.
House 这是Amber
House, this is amber.
求你了
Please.
冰冻生理盐水
Cold saline solution.
众志成城 抗震救灾/为逝者默哀 为生者祈祷
体温降到了90华氏度(32.2摄氏度)
Cool temperature down to 90.
正在旁路循环
Bypass circulating.
她稳定下来了
She's stable.
我们为什么要这样做?
Why are we doing this?
争取时间思考
Bought us time to think.
一定是外伤引发了某个之前存在的心脏问题
The trauma must have stimulated/a pre-existing heart condition.
先天性自身免疫异常/凝血功能障碍 铅中毒...
autoimmune congenital anomaly, blood/clotting disorder, lead poisoning...
任何情况都有可能
it could be anything.
太好了 让我们探个究竟
Great, let's explore that.
赶紧给她上一剂万能药
Quick, get her on panacea.
我们可以通过查找动脉阻断缩小范围
we can narrow it down by/looking for arterial blockages.
怎么找?用超声心动图?
How? On an echo?
当不存在室壁运动时/是看不到室壁运动的
Can't see wall motion/when there's no motion.
心电图?也不行/心脏正处于停止状态
Ekg, nope. Heart's in the off position.
铊扫描成像?/对一颗冷冻心脏不起作用
Thallium uptake scan?/Useless on a cold heart.
够了 我们懂了:/她的心脏停止了跳动
Yeah, we get it. Her/heart's not beating.
这令诊断变得更加困难
It's gonna make it harder to diagnose.
难道她不会在你大发牢骚时死掉/还有别的建议吗?
On the other hand, she's not gonna die/while you're whining about it. What else?
还有一个方法可以缩小范围
There is another way to narrow it down.
如果你在车祸前真的看到了Amber的症状
If you really did see a symptom/in amber before the crash,
毒扁豆碱上次帮你恢复了记忆
physostigmine helped/your memory last time.
干脆用氰化物(剧毒药)得了
Why not cyanide?
他已经衰弱不堪了/他需要的是睡眠
He's a mess. He needs to sleep.
我今早才心脏病发了一回
I had a heart attack this morning.
午饭前不能再磕药了
I can't do any more drugs till lunch.
给她做个血管造影/即便对停止的心脏也能发现损伤
Get her an angiogram. It could/show damage even in a stopped heart.
其余的人去搜索她的公寓
The rest of you search her apartment.
毒素 重金属 毒品/任何可能导致她心动过速的东西
Toxins, heavy metals, drugs, anything/that might make her heart race.
我要知道 有没有涉及诊疗/你却不能公开的事?
I need to know if there's anything medically/relevant that you couldn't share publicly.
你代表性乱者互诫会来指引我么？
Is this a philanderers/anonymous tervention?
显然你昨晚喝了酒
You were obviously drinking last night.
也许你带Amber去了酒吧
Maybe you took amber to a bar.
我一个人骑摩托车离开了这里
I left here on my motorcycle alone.
但最后你们醉醺醺地一起上了巴士
You ended up drunk on a bus together.
也许你在酒吧里遇到了Amber
Maybe you met amber in the bar.
我没有和她越轨
I was not having an affair with her.
要是你不记得就不能这么说
You can't really say that/if you don't remember.
我失去了4小时的记忆 不是4个月
I lost four hours, not four months.
也许这是第一次
Maybe it was the first time.
如果你们在一起喝的酒/你们会不会磕药了?
If you drank together, any/chance you did any drugs?
我去做毒理检测
I'll run a tox screen.
你不进来?
You coming?
邮件 寄给病人的信
Correspondence, letters to patients,
她可能在其中一个人身上/染上了某种病
she could have caught/something from one of them.
把它拷到U盘上 我们离开这里吧
Copy it to a thumb drive./Let's get out of here.
"旅游" 你知道她最近出国旅游了吗?
Travel. Do you know if she's/been out of the country recently?
是一段视频
It's just video clips.
也许她会描述她去了什么地方
Maybe she narrates where they are.
开机
and... action.
看来她没有走太远
Looks like she didn't travel very far.
- 你看起来很漂亮/- 你看起来很紧张
- You look beautiful./- You look nervous.
我从来没有干过这个
I've never done this before.
我干过 相信我 你会喜欢的
I have. Trust me. You'll love it.
这根本不相干
Not even close to relevant.
正如我们不知道什么有问题
As long as we don't know what's wrong,
我们也不知道什么才有关系
we don't know what's relevant.
是的 说不定他们俩在一堆石棉上做爱了
Yeah, maybe they're having/sex on a pile of asbestos.
去看吧
Go watch it.
如果我们在一个陌生人的家里/你会看这段视频
If we were in a stranger's house,/you'd be watching the video.
你改变了你的行为/因为她是你的朋友
You altered your behavior/because you're friends with her.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
我们根本不该治疗她
We shouldn't be treating her at all.
我去搜一下卫生间
I'm gonna search her bathroom.
你还好吗?
are you okay?
当一个幻像这么问的时候/我不能回答"很好"
Can't really say yes when/it's a hallucination asking.
别担心 你只是在作梦
Don't worry,you're just dreaming.
我在你身上看到了什么症状?
What symptom did I see in you?
- 肌肉颤动-/- 无聊
- A myoclonic jerk-/- boring.
一个异常的神经学症状被称为"无聊"?
An incredibly rare neurological/symptom is boring?
我是在别人的潜意识里吗?
Am I in someone else's subconscious?
我们昨晚干了什么?
What did we do last night?
我约了你喝酒?
Was I meeting you for a drink?
仅此而已?
Is that all it was?
一个男人觉得一个女人很漂亮/欣赏她的智慧
A man thinks a woman is beautiful,/admires her intelligence,
欣赏她为了得到自己想要的东西/不择手段
admires the way she has/to get whatever she wants,
她具备他所拥有并喜爱的特质
the things he likes about himself.
也许她...
Maybe she ...
一直以来都对他有意思
always had a little thing for him.
他的智慧 他蓝色的眼眸
His mind. His blue eyes.
但有人挡在了他们中间 所以...
But someone gets between them. So...
他们决定相约到一家偏僻的小酒吧见面
They decide to meet one night/at an out-of-the-way little bar.
这听起来是否似曾相识?
Does that sound familiar?
你对我的感觉是否似曾相识?
Do I feel familiar?
你有什么感觉?
What do you feel?
电流
Electricity.
我确信我看到了症状
I know I saw the symptom.
而这段记忆锁在我的大脑里了
I know the memory's locked in my brain.
现在我知道如何开启它了
Now I know how to get it.
不行
No.
你甚至还不知道我要说什么
You don't even know what/I'm talking about.
你需要休息
You need to rest.
我目前还没听说什么研究/把电流和休息联系起来
I have yet to hear about any/study linking electricity and rest.
深部脑刺激
Deep brain stimulation.
已经得到证实了
It's been proven.
电脉冲直接刺激脑丘下部/可以唤醒细节性记忆
Electrical impulses applied directly to the/hypothalamus could evoke detailed memories.
我说错了 在裂开的颅骨上钻洞/再打霹雳进去 的确非常有助休息
My mistake,drilling a hole and shooting lightning/bolts into an already-cracked skull is very restful,
而且绝无生命危险
it's not fatal at all.
她说得没错 你要去睡觉
She's right. You need to sleep.
脑波活动突增
Brain activity spiked.
Amber
Amber.
Amber 是我
Amber. It's me.
偶尔的突增很常见
Random spikes are common.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
我在这儿陪着你
I'm here with you.
小组有发现
The team has found something.
你能不能问问她/我们可不可以走开一下?
Can you ask her if we can be excused?
怎么了?
What?
冠状动脉血管造影呈阴性
Coronary angio was negative.
毒理测试也是
So was the tox screen.
这就是你们的发现?测试呈阴性?
That's what you found? Negative tests?
我说过了 她不磕药
I could have told you/she doesn't do drugs.
我们在她的公寓里找到了这些 对不起
We found these in her apartment. Sorry.
处方减肥丸 抗抑郁药物 安非他明
Prescription diet pills./Ssris, amphetamines.
减肥丸导致的二尖瓣结构损伤/可以解释心动过速
diet pills cause structural damage to the/mitral valve,could explain the tachycardia.
要服下足以损伤心脏的剂量/她就成瘾君子了 我能察觉到
She'd have to be an addict to take enough/for it to damage her heart. I'd know.
那你知道她把药藏在维生素瓶子里吗?
Did you know that she was/hiding them in her vitamins?
我们要让她回复体温
we have to warm her back up.
心脏重新搏动/才能做CT确定
Get her heart beating so/we can do a ct to confirm.
不 我们已经讨论过了
No, we've been over this.
重启她的心脏会导致脑损伤/并且会灼伤她的心脏肌肉
Starting her heart could cause brain/damage, could burn out the heart muscle.
在不启动的情况下测试她的心脏
Test her heart without starting it.
剖开胸腔 手指顺着静脉血管检查二尖瓣
Crack her chest open, reach a finger inside/the pulmonary vein, run it across the valve.
这个过程难道就安全了？
That's the safer course?
如果我们错了便是
It is if we're wrong.
什么时候开始 我们假定自己是错误的了?
When did we start assuming we're wrong?
- 如果这是别的病人-/- 如果二尖瓣钙化 我们就知道答案了
- If this were any other patient- - if/the valve is calcified, that's our answer.
也就可以采取治疗了 去吧
That's our cure. Go.
13.
Thirteen.
谁发现了这些减肥丸?
Who found the diet pills?
Kutner
Kutner.
你甚至没进卫生间 对不敌?
You didn't even go in/the bathroom, did you?
你突然在讨论时变得沉默了
You're suddenly mute/in the differentials.
一个吹气娃娃都比你有用
A blow-up doll would be more useful.
还有 是的 这是我第一次用/吹气娃娃来打反面比方
And yes, that's the first time I've ever/implied something negative about a blow-up doll.
这是Amber 我不--
It's amber.I don't-
正常来说 我会很感兴趣/但今天 我不在乎
normally, I'd be fascinated./Today, don't care.
不管是什么 忘了它 专心工作
Get over whatever it is and do your job.
等等 看她的眼睛
wait. Look at her eye.
出现了黄疸
She's jaundiced.
她的肝脏正在衰竭
Her liver's shutting down.
减肥药不会引起肝脏衰竭
Diet pills don't kill the liver.
把她送回重症监护室
Put her back in icu.
肾脏衰竭表示病原正在扩散
liver failure means whatever/this thing is it's spreading,
即使她处于冷冻状态
despite the fact that she's frozen.
肝脏和心脏衰竭可能是抗胰蛋白酶缺乏
hepatic and heart failure could/mean antitrypsinase deficiency.
我们可以用一根针探进她的肝部
We can stick a needle in her liver.
如果看到纤维化 她就对了
If we see fibrosis,she's right.
Amber喝雪利酒吗?
Does amber drink sherry?
心脏也可以解释
And the cardio fits just as well.
但我们没有办法知道/我们量不了她的体温
But there's no way we can tell,/since we can't take her temperature.
我做了个梦
I had a dream.
她给我倒了一杯雪利酒
She was pouring me a glass.
但我只喝苏格兰威士忌 啤酒/杜松子酒和朗姆酒...
And since I'm a scotch,/beer, gin, and rum man...
如果我们让她恢复体温/就可以知道她有没有受到感染了
if we warm her back up,we should be/able to tell if she's got an infection.
没错 病原恣意扩散直至杀死她/我们就能得出诊断了
Yes, we can get a diagnosis by letting/the disease run rampant until it kills her.
要是病原正在扩散/我们必须使它慢下来
If it's spreading, we/need to slow this even more.
我们要把她的体温降得更低
We've gotta cool her down further.
我知道你爱她/你怕她会死
I know you love her and/you're scared she's gonna die.
但把体温一降再降不是治疗的方法
But just making her colder/and colder isn't a cure.
不能解决现实问题
It's not dealing with the reality.
雪利酒代表某些东西
Sherry means something.
Amber根本不喝雪利酒/House 你能不能回到--
amber doesn't even drink/sherry. House.Can we get back--
她喝的话就代表不了什么
if she did drink sherry,it/would mean nothing.
正因为她不喝 显然我的潜意识/想要暗示某些事情
Since she doesn't, my subconscious is/obviously trying to make some other point.
巴士路线的第三个路口/右拐有个Sharrie酒吧
There's a sharrie's bar on/third right off the bus route.
Wilson说的没错 要再降低她的体温
Wilson's right. We/need to make her colder.
往她身上放更多的冰块/只会推迟诊断
Putting more ice on her is/just delaying the diagnosis.
不是身上 是体内
Not on, in.
用冰浆填满她的肺部
Fill her lungs with slurry.
- 你要去哪里?/- 带Wilson出去喝杯酒
- Where are you going?/- I'm taking wilson out for a drink.
是这个地方吗?
Is this the place?
也许
Maybe.
我猜你来这儿...
I assume you are here...
是为了这个
for these.
你有没有见过我和一个/高个白种女人一起来?
Did you see me here with/a tall blonde woman?
有 你喝到第七杯苏格兰威士忌时 她来了
Yeah, I think she joined/you after scotch number seven.
她样子像是病了吗?
Did she seem sick?
她打喷嚏
She sneezed.
我给了她一张餐巾
I gave her a napkin.
你看到她的痰是什么颜色的吗?
Did you see the color of the sputum?
你是说鼻涕吧
I assume sputum means snot.
听着 我在这儿看到了/无数醉醺醺的小妞
Look, I see a lot of/drunk chicks in here.
我可没工夫闲下来分析/你女友鼻涕疙瘩的颜色
I didn't have time to stop and analyze/the color of your girlfriend's boogers.
她不是我女朋友 天才
She's not my girlfriend,genius.
她很性感 你似乎对她有意思/她还给你买了酒
She was hot, you seemed into/her, and she bought you drinks.
至少在昨晚 她是你女朋友
Last night,she was your girlfriend.
痰液带血表示有寄生虫
Blood in the sputum could mean parasites.
最近去过旅游吗?
Any recent travel?
你似乎对她有意思?
You seemed into her?
如果他有脑子就不用当酒保了
If he had a brain, he/wouldn't be tending bar.
新的症状是 打喷嚏
Sneezing's a new symptom.
假设流鼻涕是因为感染
Let's assume the runny/nose means an infection.
House和你说了什么
What did house have to say?
他说我是被狼养大的狼孩/所以用同只手使用刀和叉
He told me I was raised by wolves and that's/why I use the same hand for my fork and knife.
灌冰浆的管子不是这条
Not that one. The slurry tube.
我明白这次和以往不同
I know this is different.
但谁都难免一死
But it's not. Everyone dies.
她还活着
She's not dead.
可你清楚她就快不行了
You're reacting this/way because she might be--soon.
没错 为什么你一点都不伤心
Yeah, I am. Why aren't you?
我是印度人 姓氏却是kutner.
I'm an indian guy named kutner.
你未怀疑过我来自什么样的家庭吗
Ever wonder what happened to my parents?
- 抱歉 没注意过/- 那是我才六岁
- I'm sorry,I didn't-/- I was six years old.
我经常放学后在父母店里帮忙
I used to like helping out in my/parents' store after school.
一个男人走进来抢劫
Guy walks into rob the place.
杀害了我的父母 这一点也不公平
Ends up shooting them both. Wasn't fair.
我过了很久才接受这个事实/但是生活就是这样
Took years,but I had to accept/that's just the way it was.
你到底要不要帮我往肺里塞冰浆
So you gonna help me fill/her lungs up or not?
告诉我 你们发现了/肝脏切片查出浸润 微小发炎
Tell me that the liver biopsy showed/infiltrates, minor inflammation.
没错/你怎么--?
Yeah./How--?
因为纸巾上的鼻涕
Snot on a napkin.
- 心脏的问题,再加上肺浸润.../- 是乙型肝炎
- Add the heart,infiltrates.../- hep B.
给她注射病毒抗原干扰素
Start her on iv interferon.
我去告诉Wilson
I'll go tell wilson.
好主意
Good idea.
因为我才是那个 刚经历车祸/早上还心脏病突发 需要睡觉的人
And I'll go nap because I was concussed/last night and had a heart attack this morning.
我去告诉Wilson 你去休息
I'll tell wilson;you go sleep.
乙型肝炎? 真是荒谬
Hepatitis b is a lame diagnosis.
老天 我睡着后比醒着更受折磨
Oh, god, I get less rest when I'm asleep.
我死而复生 这就是你的反应?
I rise from the dead,and/that's the reaction I get?
对不起 如果我知道/我会提前离开犹太人教派
I'm sorry. If I had known, I would/have started a breakaway jewish sect.
乙肝符合你的症状
Hep b fits.
你干吗这么做
Why are you doing that?
因为乙肝不符合
Because hep b doesn't fit.
把她翻过来
Turn her ver.
我们正要开始注射干扰素的第二步
We're about to start a/second course of interferon.
把她翻过来 也许就不用注射了
Which she might not/need once you turn her over.
她的腰背处
Small of her back.
有淤伤
she's bruised.
-这个有什么重要的?/- 靠近看
- Why is that significant?/- Look closer.
有皮疹
a rash.
你怎么知道是在她腰背处
How did you know what/was on the small of her back?
如果不是我在做梦/就是我的记忆开始恢复
Either I'm still asleep,/or I'm starting to remember.
看起来象流行性感冒的皮疹
looks like an influenza rash.
感冒不会造成她的多个器官衰竭
The flu wouldn't be/killing her organs one by one.
皮肌炎
Dermatomyositis.
那不会造成她心跳过快
Wouldn't speed up her heart.
也许是对干扰素的过敏反应
Maybe it's an allergic/reaction to the interferon.
难道两天前我在公车上看到的皮疹/是对刚刚注射的干扰素过敏
Yes, the symptom that I saw on the bus was a rare interferon/allergy that flares up two days before you take it.
你怎么看到她背后皮疹的
How did you see the rash down there?
我不知道 也许她弯下了腰
I don't know. Maybe she leaned over.
也许根本不是皮疹
Maybe it's not a rash at all.
可能是脓疮
It could be an abscess.
13 插针进去/如果有脓 Foreman就对了
Thirteen, stick a needle in there./If there's pus,foreman's right.
超声波比较安全
Ultrasound is safer.
我又不是要你拿针穿透她
I'm not asking you to stick a/needle all the way through.
Taub 你来做
Taub, you do it.
等一下 我可以做
No, wait, I can do it.
很显然 你不行
No, apparently, you can't.
没有滑动迹象
It's not fluctuant.
干净的 没脓
Clear. It's not pus.
说明是个囊包
Means it's vesicular.
落基山斑疹热/(由扁虱传播)
Rocky mountain spotted fever.
我们上周和朋友一起吃饭
We had dinner with a friend last week.
我们帮他们遛了遛狗
We walked their dogs.
她可能沾到了虱子
I guess she could have gotten a tick.
可以用强力霉素治疗
It's treatable. Doxycycline.
抗生素需要8个小时才能见效
Allow eight hours for the/antibiotics to take effect,
到时再回升体温 激活她心脏
then we warm her up,shock her heart.
等一等 等一等
Wait a minute,wait a minute.
如果诊断错误 把她解冻可能会杀了她
If we're wrong, restarting her/heart could kill her.
先做例血培养
Run blood cultures first.
最快的治疗办法就是对症下药
The fastest way to test is to treat.
就算错了 也有时间换其他治疗方案
If we're wrong,it still should/give us time to try something else.
没有百分百把握/我不准你们解冻她
We are not starting her heart/until we're 100% certain.
从来没有百分百把握
We're never 100% certain.
先做例血培养
Run the blood cultures.
结果确定后 再给她解冻
After we get confirmation,then/we'll restart her heart.
是他错了
He's wrong.
而且你很清楚是他的错
And you know he's wrong.
你不能因为家属的情绪/而动摇自己的立场
You can't change your mind just/because a family member starts crying.
他们肯定会恐惧的
They're always scared.
听我的 去做例血培养
I said,run the blood cultures.
抱歉 站得太开
sorry. Wide stance.
你说对了 我遇到麻烦了
You're right. I'm screwing up.
你为什么这么觉得
Why are you screwing up?
我根本就不喜欢她
I didn't even like her.
你很恨她?
Did you hate her?
不至于希望她死掉啊
Not enough to want her dead.
那么就不是因为内疚
So it's not guilt.
那么剩下的就是 恐惧了
That just leaves fear.
一个快要不行的年轻女人
A young woman dying.
事实上 一个快要不行的年轻医生
A young doctor dying, in fact.
听起来是不是挺耳熟?
Does that sound familiar?
是 我有可能得了亨廷顿舞蹈症/但我有心理准备
Yeah, I'm at risk for/huntington'S. I've dealt with it.
你连测试都没做
By not getting tested?
你处理的方法就是无视它的存在?
Dealing with it by not dealing with it.
干得真不错
It's clearly working beautifully.
你才是最爱躲避问题的第一名!
You are the champion of not/dealing with your problems.
我孙子送我的水杯上写的就是这句
My grandson gave me a mug that says that.
好了 怀柔政策结束/你先去测试
Okay. Enough/hand-holding. Deal with it.
然后回去工作 或者直接走人
Get back in there./Or pack up your stuff.
你表现的还不如我好
You're screwing up this/case worse than I am.
* 爱 恋 是一个动词 *
* Love, love is a verb *
* 迷 恋 是个进行词 *
* love is a doing word *
* 羽毛随着我的呼吸 上扬 *
* feathers on my breath *
* 激情温柔的摇摆着我 让我轻飘欲然 *
* gentle impulsion shakes/me,makes me lighter *
* 羽毛随着我的呼吸 上扬 *
* feathers on my breath *
* 眼泪湮没在火焰里 *
* teardrop on the fire *
* 羽毛随着我的呼吸 上扬 *
* feathers on my breath *
House会把病人害死的
House is gonna kill the patient.
你们在做什么
What are you--what/are you doing?
她体温回升到了80度 (摄氏26度)
She's up to 80 degrees.
我们要让她心脏重启
We're gonna restart her heart.
你们不能这么做
No, you're not.
还有时间让她体温回降
There's still time to undo/this, cool her back down.
你这么做不正确
You weren't taking the safe approach.
我们必须知道抗生素是否奏效
We've got to know if the/antibiotics are working.
她的脑部活动开始下降
Her eeg's slowed.
Amber  Amber.
Amber. Amber.
干得好 连是什么还没诊断出来/你就让病疾扩散到了她的脑部
Well done. We still don't know what it is,/but you've just let it spread to her brain.
跟我讲得一模一样!/现在病情已经恶化到了她的脑子
this is exactly what I said would/happen. It's in her brain now.
大脑的恶化给了我们新的症状
brain involvement gives us a new symptom.
- 本来不会这么严重,如果不是你--/- 这是病情的正常扩散
- That wouldn't be there if you hadn't-/- it's where the disease was going.
- 我们必须掌握/- 这个不是你该做的决定!
- We needed to know that./- This was not your decision to make.
你背着我 背着House 擅自做了决定
You went behind my back./You went behind house's back.
吵个不停
Inside voices.
House想解冻她
House wanted to warm her up.
是你逼他内疚 让他改变主意
You just guilt him into/changing his mind.
心脏 肝脏 皮疹 现在是她的大脑
Heart, liver, rash,and now her brain.
自体免疫性疾病
Autoimmune fits best.
车祸外伤是导火索
Crash trauma could have set it off.
开始给她服用强的松/然后把她重新解冻
Start her on prednisone,/then we'll warm her up again.
House, 如果是其他类型的感染/类固醇会破坏掉她整个免疫系统
House, if this is some other infection,/the steroids will trash her immune system.
他是医生 你是家属
He's the attending. You're the family.
好好陪着病人吧
Go spend more time with the patient.
你不能这么做
You can't do this.
抗辩很无力
That's not a good argument.
根本算不上抗辩
It's not an argument at all.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Cuddy是对的 我恐惧到不敢作任何选择
Cuddy's right. I was/afraid to do anything.
我原以为只要暂停着/一切都会好转
I thought if everything just/stopped, it would be okay.
会好起来的
And it's gonna be.
Taub正在执行治疗方案
Taub's starting the treatment.
- 我们已经尽了力/- 还没有
- We're doing everythi-/- not everything.
在给她解冻之前...
Before you warm her up...
你说过你愿意去接受深度电击
you said you wanted to/try deep brain stimulation.
但是现在没这个必要
But there's no reason.
我们掌握了病症 我也想了起来
We know the symptom,we know what I saw.
如果不是因为皮疹呢
What if it's not the rash?
如果皮疹是在救护车上/或者做旁路循环时发现的呢
What if you noticed the rash in the ambulance/or when we were putting her on bypass?
如果还有你没想起来的呢
What if there is still something/else stuck inside your head?
你认为我该舍命救Amber
You think I should risk/my life to save amber's.
插入探针到你的下丘脑腹部
Inserting the ipg probe into/your ventral hypothalamus.
给我三伏电力
Give me three volts.
我听不到他讲什么
I can't hear him.
他是谁
can't hear who?
一切都是黑白色
Everything's in black and white.
谁在讲话 Amber在那里吗
who was talking? Is amber there?
你们需要刺激我的下丘脑/不是轻轻抚摸它
You're supposed to be jolting my/hypothalamus, not petting it.
我们不想超过负荷
We don't want to overload it.
我都豁出去了 至少让我看场有声电影
As long as I'm risking my life, I/might as well be watching a talkie.
从三伏增加到五伏
Increasing from three to five volts.
发送脉冲波
Sending impulse.
车钥匙我先替你保管
You're not getting them back.
你把我钥匙拿走 总得让我打个电话吧
Hey, you take my keys, you/gotta give me a phone call.
你在打给谁?
who are you calling?
打去你家
Dial-a-wilson.
我当时在值班
I was on call.
Amber在家
Amber was home.
我告诉她去找你
I told her to find you.
让你接我回家
Have you pick me up.
我说了叫你找Wilson来
I said to find wilson.
他在上班 我决定代替他 忍受你的羞辱
He's working. And I'm willing to/suffer this indignity on his behalf.
她看起来不舒服吗
did she seem sick?
- 还没/- 时间到了 我们走
- Not yet./- Come on. Time to go.
再来一杯
Need another round.
然后给这位女士也来一杯
And a drink for what/passes for a lady around here.
- 你爱喝什么?/- 什么都不喝 我们这就走
- What's your poison?/- Nothing. We're leaving.
我们这就走..  对了 是大都会鸡尾酒
We're leaving, leaving,/leaving,leaving, leaving-- cosmos.
我记得Wilson买过酸莓果汁
I remember wilson/buying cranberry juice.
我再来一杯  然后给她一杯大都会
I'll have another. And/she'll have a cosmopolitan.
你逼我喝酒 我也不会领情的/你不是要回家吗 快走
The obstinate drunk thing is not/flattering. Come on. You called for a ride.
把你的酒喝掉 不然我两杯都要
Drink ur drink, or I'll drink 'em both.
就一杯
One.
然后你乖乖跟我走
And you leave voluntarily.
我们走吧
Let's go.
再来一杯大都会
We need another cosmo here.
她打了喷嚏
She sneezed.
- 什么颜色/- 谢谢
- What color is it?/- Thanks.
看起来是鼻涕 应该是感冒
Looks like snot. It seems like a cold.
没有别的
Nothing else?
没有
No.
你要去哪?
where are you going?
你觉得我会付账吗
You think I paid?
House你要去哪/你走路都不稳了
House, what are you/doing? You can barely walk.
回家 我要坐公车
Go home. I'll take the bus.
嘿 你们谁来付账
hey, someone's gotta pay for this.
你忘记了这个
You forgot something.
你从来不知道什么叫放弃 对不对
You don't give up,do you?
对 我就那么白痴
Yeah, I'm an idiot that way.
你这么做为了我还是Wilson?
You doing this for me or for wilson?
当然是Wilson
For wilson.
那可真让人感动/干杯
Well, then it's even more/impressive. Salut.
该死 你有纸巾吗
Ugh, damn, do you have a kleenex?
我有条袖子
I got a sleeve.
确切说的 两条
I got two, actually.
我需要更多 我得了重感冒
I need more than that./I'm getting that nasty flu.
就是这样? 感冒?
Is that it? The flu?
没有其他罕见并发症吗?
Is there any rare complication?
没有 这解释了皮疹 解释不了别的
No. It would explain the/rash,but nothing else.
- 除非.../- 什么?
- Unless.../- what?
不要吃它
Don't do it.
不是感冒 是因为她吃的药
It wasn't the flu. It's/what she did for it.
她是服用三环癸胺导致中毒
She has amantadine poisoning.
而车祸毁了她的肾脏
The crash destroyed her kidneys.
她的身体无法过滤那些毒素
Her body couldn't filter the drugs.
她过量服用三环癸胺/解释了心脏和肝脏的衰竭...
She ods on amantadine,explains/the heart, the liver...
我们只要给她做血液透析/把毒素滤去就行了
we just need to start her on/dialysis and flush the drugs out.
怎么了?
What? What's wrong?
三环癸胺会与蛋白质结合在一起
Amantadine binds with proteins.
透析无法从滤去蛋白质
Dialysis can't clear/it out of the blood.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
Amber.
他在抽搐  Wilson 快过来帮忙
Seizing. Wilson, I need help here.
House 处于局部痉挛综合症中
House suffered a complex partial seizure.
巨大晃动加大了他的头骨裂缝/造成了脑出血
The violent shaking widened his/skull fracture, causing a brain bleed.
在他恢复意识之前/我们无法估测是否造成了精神损伤
We won't know if there's any cognitive/impairment until he's out of the coma.
他对三环癸胺的诊断是对的
He was right about the amantadine.
Amber的身体无法滤出毒素
Amber's body couldn't filter it out.
所以她长时间心跳加速
That's what caused her heart to/beat too fast for too long.
造成了无法修补的结构损伤
It caused irreparable structural damage.
无论是电击或者冰冻她
Didn't matter if/they shocked her or froze her.
她的心脏在救护车上就停止跳动了
Her heart was dead once it/stopped in that ambulance.
不能做心脏移植手术吗?
What about a new heart? Transplant?
她所有的器官都已损坏
All of her organs are damaged.
不够资格做手术移植
She can't qualify.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do.
已经没有办法挽救了
Nothing we could have done.
该读取死亡时间了
We should call time of death.
从医学上讲 她仍然活着
Well, technically,she's still alive.
用旁路循环 她可以再支持几个小时
Could probably survive a/few more hours on bypass.
我们可以停用麻药 让她苏醒过来/给你们一个机会---
We could wean her off anesthesia,/wake her up, give you a chance to--
那样太残忍了 不要---
it would be/cruel. Don't--
叫醒她 再见她一面
wake amber up.See her again.
告诉她 她对你来说有多重要
Tell her what she means to you.
把她叫醒 告诉她 她就快---
Wake her up to tell/her that she's--that she's--
把她唤醒 你们好向对方互道珍重
You are waking her up so that you/can both say good-bye to each other.
她会希望能跟你道别的
She would want it.
你现在是在医院
You're in the hospital.
在用旁路循环
I'm on bypass.
是的
Yeah.
还记得发生了什么吗?
Do you remember what happened?
我上了辆公车
Got on the bus.
我不该上那趟车的
I shouldn't have gotten on the bus.
不 不 这不是你的错
No. No, it's not your fault.
- 不是你的错/- 情况有多严重?
- It's not your fault./- How bad?
你心跳过速
You had tachycardia.
因为肾衰竭 情况复杂了
It's complicated by/complete renal failure.
心跳过速恶化成室颤
The tachycardia degenerated into v-fib,
随之肝衰竭
followed by hepatic failure.
因为感冒药?
The flu pills?
是的
Yeah.
我要死了
I'm dead.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我们该去道个别
we should say good-bye.
她不喜欢我们
She didn't even like us.
我们喜欢她
We liked her.
我们喜欢?
Did we?
现在喜欢了
We do now.
说什么?
What do we say?
什么都不用说
We don't need to say anything.
* "死海文书"重见天日 *
* This my excavation and to...*
* 今天属于昆兰地区 *
* day is kumran *
* 一切都从此刻开始 *
* everything that/happens is from now on *
* 暴雨如瀑 万物停滞 *
* this is pouring rain/this is paralyzed...*
我累了
I'm tired.
是合眼睡觉的时候了
I think it's time to go to sleep.
再等一会儿
Just a little longer.
我们在一起 多久都嫌不够
We're always gonna/want just a little longer.
我想我没法面对
I don't think I can do it.
没事的
It's okay.
怎么会没事 你怎么会说没事?
It's not okay. Why is it okay with you?
你为什么不生气?
Why aren't you angry?
我...不希望...
That's... not...
生命最后时刻心怀遗憾
the last feeling I want to experience.
* 声音响起 珍宝被开启 被取出 *
* The sound of the/unlocking and the lift away *
* 你的爱 伴着我 不用担心 *
* your love will be safe with me *
你死了
You're dead.
人人都会死
Everybody dies.
我死了吗?
Am I dead?
还没
Not yet.
- 我该死的/- 为什么?
- I should be./- Why?
因为生命不该如此不公正
Because life shouldn't be random.
孤独厌世的瘾君子该死在车祸里
Because lonely,misanthropic drug/addicts should die in bus crashes,
半夜被人从家里拖出来帮朋友的
and young do-gooders in love
年轻恋人该幸免于难
who get dragged out of their apartment in the/middle of the night should walk away clean.
自怜可不像你
Self-pity isn't like you.
是啊 从自我怨恨和自我毁灭/衍生出自怜
No, well,I'm branching out from/self-loathing and self-destruction.
Wilson会恨我的
Wilson is gonna hate me.
你挺活该的
You kind of deserve it.
他是我最好的朋友
He's my best friend.
我知道
I know.
现在呢?
What now?
我跟你一起待在这儿
I could stay here with you.
下车
Get off the bus.
- 我不能/- 为什么?
- I can't./- Why not?
因为
Because.
因为在这儿不会痛
Because it doesn't hurt here.
我不想...我不想觉得疼痛
I let it... I don't want to be in pain.
不想感到痛苦
I don't want to be miserable.
我不想他恨我
And I don't want him to hate me.
你不能总得到你想要的
Well, you can't always get what you want.
* 有些时光从身边流逝 *
* There are times that walk from you *
* 仿佛逝去的午后 *
* Like some passing afternoon *
* 夏日温暖了她蜜月的窗*
* Summer warmed the open/window of her honeymoon *
* 她在院落焚烧落叶 *
* And she chose a yard to burn *
* 土地记住了她*
* But the ground remembers her *
嘿 我在这儿
hey, I'm here.
听得到我说话就眨眨眼
Blink if you can hear me.
不 嘘 别说话 好好休息
No, shh,don't try to talk. Just rest.
"亨廷顿舞蹈症: --/* 秋天吹落床上她叠好的棉被 *
* Autumn blew the quilt right/off the perfect bed she made *
--阳性"/* 她开始相信 *
* And she's chosen to believe *
* 她母亲哼唱的赞美诗 *
* In the hymns her mother sings *
* 星期日在落叶堆中拉起孩子 *
* Sunday pulls it's children from/their piles of fallen leaves *
*帆船驶过 *
* There are sailing ships that pass *
* 穿过青草地里我们的身体 *
* All our bodies in the grass *
* 春天呼唤她的孩子/她终于放手让他们走 *
* Springtime calls her children/until she lets them go at last *
* 她决定留在哪里 *
* And she's chosen where to be *
* 虽然她遗落了的结婚戒指 *
* Though she's lost her wedding ring *
* 就安放在九重葛花籽瓶的附近 *
* Somewhere near her misplaced/jar of Bougainvillea seeds *
* 有些事怎么都想不起来 *
* There are things we can't recall *
* 好像黑夜终会将我们吞没 *
* Blind as night that finds us all *
* 冬天藏起了她的孩子/她易碎的瓷娃娃 *
* Winter tucks her children/in, her fragile china dolls *
* 她还会帮他缝补破衣裳 *
* But she'll mend his tattered clothes *
* 他们还会亲吻 似乎他们知道  *
* and they'll kiss as if they know  *
* 我们的骨骼里都睡着一个婴孩 *
* A baby sleeps in all our bones *
* 如此害怕孤单 *
* so scared to be alone *
对不起 我不在 我去接House
SORRY I'M NOT HERE.WENT TO PICK UP HOUSE